tclusa.com 2019-06-07

# Terms/Privacy | TCL

## Privacy Policy & Terms of Use

**Updated: January 10, 2019**

**Effective Date: January 10, 2019**

**What was recently updated:** What was recently updated: This Privacy Policy was most recently updated to include references to additional products including headphones, sound bars, and appliances.

* * *

At TCL, we value your trust and confidence. We believe that we earn your trust and confidence when we continually bring you exceptional products and services and consistently do so in a private and secure manner. We created this Privacy Policy to inform you of our commitment to you, our customer.

This Privacy Policy applies to information collected by TTE Technology, Inc. (“TCL,” “company”, “we”, “our”, or “us”) in connection with the  _[www.tclusa.com](http://www.tclusa.com/)_  website, including product warranty registration and customer support inquiries, and all products including TCL televisions and all models of the TCL® Roku TV™, all models of TCL headphones, all models of TCL sound bars, and all models of TCL air conditioners and dehumidifiers. This includes information collected online through our website, information that may be collected through third party platforms (e.g., social media, social networks, and sweepstakes and giveaways conducted through third party websites and applications), mobile applications, sweepstakes and giveaways managed and/or administered by TCL, direct marketing campaigns conducted by TCL or a partner organization selling TCL-branded products, or other online communications, as well as the potential for any offline communications (collectively, hereinafter referred to as “TCL Services”).

This Privacy Policy explains what information may be collected through the TCL Services, how any information that is collected may be used and/or shared with other third-party companies or organizations, the steps we take to safeguard your information, and how you may access and control your information in relation to our marketing and sales communications, and any business activities. By using the TCL Services, you agree to the collection, use, and disclosure of your information as described in this Privacy Policy.  If you do not agree, we ask that you do not use the  _[www.tclusa.com](http://www.tclusa.com/)_  website or the TCL Services.

**1\. INFORMATION COLLECTION**

**Information You Provide to Us**

When you use the TCL Services, we may ask you to provide certain personal information to register your product for warranty coverage.  For example, on the  _[www.tclusa.com](http://www.tclusa.com/)_  website, customers can conveniently register their new TCL product by visiting a webpage, providing the requested information, and submitting the information. Customers are not required to set up an account or provide any method of payment. Customers are asked to provide personal information including a name, telephone number, e-mail address, mailing or product delivery address, date of purchase, name of retailer, product model number, and product serial number. We may ask for similar information when you enter into a sweepstakes, giveaway, or other promotion; when you request customer support; or, when you otherwise communicate with us.

We (or our marketing partner, warranty service provider(s), or other business partners or affiliates) may collect information about you, including personal information, such as name, e-mail address, telephone number, mailing or product delivery address, date of birth (for the purpose of verifying age in sweepstakes or giveaways (or to ensure you are older than thirteen (13) years of age), gender, and certain other demographic information.

**_Information You Provide When You Make a Purchase._**  If you make a purchase of one of our products from an authorized retailer, you may be required to provide a form of payment that may include a credit/debit card number and related financial data (such as CVV, card expiration date, and the billing address), or other payment information (e.g., mobile payment methods), depending on the form of payment you select. This information is not provided to TCL by the retailer.

In the ordinary course of business, TCL does not have access to any of the customer information you have provided to your retailer, whether that retailer is a chain of stores operating throughout the United States, or a website selling products throughout the world. In the event you communicate about the product with the retailer where the product was originally purchased, the retailer may connect you with a TCL customer service employee or representative. As such, certain personal information may be transferred by the retailer to TCL in an effort to better serve you, to facilitate communication, and to resolve any questions you may have about the product. There are similar instances when your personal information could be obtained by TCL’s customer service when working to assist you in resolving a question about your product, and then this information may in-turn be provided to the retailer.

**_Information That You Disclose about Third Parties_** **.** You may determine to provide us with third-party information (e.g., name, email, address) in order for us to recommend products to those third parties. TCL requests that you do not provide us with third party personal information, unless those third parties have provided their personal and direct consent to do so. We prefer each individual to personally provide their own information. We do not actively seek required consent from third parties after receiving such third-party information, and as such, in the event we are provided third party personal information we will not retain or utilize such information.

**_Information You Provide to Us Through Social Media_** **.** You may also enter into sweepstakes and/or giveaways sponsored by TCL or an affiliated third party, and/or administered by TCL or a third-party facilitator (e.g., third party website or application), and the information you provide during your registration for those sweepstakes and giveaways is collected by TCL, and information you may provide in the course of registering or setting up an account with such third-party facilitator may be provided to TCL (as determined on a case-by-case basis). You may also utilize certain social media features to “like” or “add as friend” to your social media account TCL’s social media account or presence. When you do, TCL may automatically, or manually, receive certain information from your social media account. Such information disclosure is based upon the privacy settings on those sites that you have elected to set, as well as any automatic settings in place. This may include, but may not be limited to, your name, your user name or account name, any demographic information you have provided on your account, your mailing address and other contact information, your location, certain interests you may have provided on your account, and any information from social media and online activity on your social media account(s).

**Information Collected Automatically**

Whenever you visit the  _[www.tclusa.com](http://www.tclusa.com/)_  website, or certain third party web sites that may be affiliated with TCL, we (or those third parties) may use a variety of technologies that automatically or passively collect information about your online activity. This information may be collected in the following ways:

**_Internet Usage Information:_**   TCL uses cookies, and may use other methods of identification commonly used on websites today including software enabling mobile analytics, log files, web beacons, pixel tags, or other technologies and methods in order to collect information about your online internet activity, online (and online mobile) advertising, and to allow us, or third parties engaged by us or affiliated with us, to track certain statistical information to enable more applicable content and advertising and to improve our services and offerings.

For example, we may (or through affiliated or contracted third parties) automatically collect certain non-personal information from you and your computer or mobile device, including the type of browser you use, the manufacturer of the mobile device you are using, the operating system on your device, the mobile carrier that enables your mobile device network, products and/or services you purchase or have shown interest in, your phone number on your mobile device (if applicable), your device and/or mobile device activity, and other similar information. We may also automatically collect information about your use of the  _[www.tclusa.com](http://www.tclusa.com/)_  website, including the date and time you visit the website, the pages on the website that you visit, the amount of time you spend viewing or using the website, the number of times you return to the website, other site usage data, and other sites that you may visit.

**_Information About Your Device_** **.** We may automatically collect a record of your IP address, or other similar identifying record of your computer or mobile device, that you utilize to access  _[www.tclusa.com](http://www.tclusa.com/)_ , including the computer/mobile device model information, and in the case of a mobile device, information identifying your mobile network. We may use this to, among other things, analyze trends, track the usage of web pages, mobile applications and online activities, to obtain general demographic information for aggregate usage, and to target and/or re-target online and mobile online advertising to you on the various computers and mobile devices you may use.

**_Geolocation Data_** **:**  We may collect information about the location of your computer and/or mobile device when you visit  _[www.tclusa.com](http://www.tclusa.com/)_. When using a mobile device and turning on the Bluetooth, the Wi-Fi, or other geolocation-enabling functions when you access  _[www.tclusa.com](http://www.tclusa.com/)_  or use certain third-party platforms enabling the entry into sweepstakes and/or giveaways sponsored by TCL, we may collect your geolocation information and utilize such information. Please see the corresponding product manuals and other supporting information for your computer and/or mobile device(s) that provides information on how the features and settings enabling geolocation and other similar identifying information can be accessed and switched on and off.

**_Third Party Service Providers_** **.** We may use third party services, companies, organizations, applications, and other affiliated entities to support the  _[www.tclusa.com](http://www.tclusa.com/)_  website and to enable, manage, facilitate, advertise, and administer sweepstakes and giveaways sponsored by TCL.  Some of these third parties may utilize technologies that include, but are not limited to, cookies, pixel tags, log files, and/or other technologies, to enable the receiving of, and the collection and storage of, information on our behalf.

**Information Received from Third Parties**

We may receive information about you from certain trusted third-party vendors, affiliates, contracted companies, or other sources. For example, this may include information from publicly-available sources that may also include personal information such as your demographic information and other similar information. We may also receive information about you from our partner companies and from third-party service providers.

We may use this information to assist us in maintaining the accuracy of the information that we collect, to provide a more personalized experience, to inform you of products and other offers that you may be interested in, to provide a metric to measure quality, and for other business purposes.

**Aggregating the Information**

We may aggregate the information we receive directly from you with information we receive from third-party sources. This aggregated information may be used in any of the manners outlined in this Privacy Policy.

**2\. THIS IS HOW WE USE THE COLLECTED INFORMATION**

We may use the information about you for a variety of business purposes, including for example:

**For Customer Service Purposes, such as to:**

  * Enable us to respond to your questions, comments, product requests, and to provide customer service;
  * Manage customer service communications between you and TCL;
  * Troubleshoot product-related issues;
  * Enable the return of a product, and enable the delivery of a product, to or from a customer by TCL, a retailer, and/or TCL’s warranty administrator(s);
  * Verify your identity for warranty administration purposes; and,
  * Enable the protection and security of TCL customers, TCL’s  _[www.tclusa.com](http://www.tclusa.com/)_  website, and TCL products.

**For Marketing, Advertising, and Analytics Purposes, including to:**

  * Enable consumers to enter sweepstakes and giveaways sponsored by, and/or administered by, TCL;
  * Enable consumers that win sweepstakes and/or giveaways to receive prizes or certain product and/or company information;
  * Perform market research, and measure the efficacy of certain TCL promotions and marketing initiatives;
  * Improve TCL products and enhance the  _[www.tclusa.com](http://www.tclusa.com/)_  website;
  * Provide consumers with specific information for how to recycle or donate their used products in their communities; and,
  * Communicate directly with consumers to understand your needs and answer your questions, in accordance with any previously selected permissions you may have provided.

**3\. INFORMATION SHARING**

The information collected or generated through your use of the  _[www.tclusa.com](http://www.tclusa.com/)_  website may be shared by you or by us as described below.

**Sharing of Information by You**

The services on the  _[www.tclusa.com](http://www.tclusa.com/)_  website offer many methods to register your product, as well as request additional information from customer service or ask a product question.

The information you provide on the  _[www.tclusa.com](http://www.tclusa.com/)_  website while registering your product, requesting additional information from customer service or asking a product question, is submitted to TCL and is not visible to other companies or the general public. Information you provide when entering a sweepstakes or giveaway through the  _[www.tclusa.com](http://www.tclusa.com/)_  website, or through a third-party administrator, may be shared between TCL and the third -party administrator.

The Sharing of Your Information with Others by Us

TCL may share the information and data collected from you (or about you) in the following ways:

**_With Our Affiliates_** **.** We may share your information with our parent companies, subsidiaries, and other affiliated companies for internal corporate reasons, for other business reasons, or for certain operational reasons.

**_Third-Party Providers of Services_** _._   We may share your personal information or data with third-party service providers engaged by TCL. These third parties may provide TCL with certain business functions, and certain professional and/or technical support functions. This may include, but may not be limited to: companies providing certain integrated technologies in the products; technology licensors or licensees; service providers that may host information or provide certain technological capabilities; payment processors (if applicable); data analysis; third-party warranty administration; customer service and product shipping, delivery, and set-up; and, sponsors or other organizations that participate in, sponsor, or administer promotions including sweepstakes and giveaways.

**_Additional Third Parties._** _ _ Your personal information and data may also be shared with companies, organizations, and/or others not referred to above in connection with marketing, promotions, and product offers. It is also possible that at the time of your submittal of personal information, we may identify additional parties that may receive some or all of your information if you provide the consent for such sharing of information.

**_Sweepstakes, Giveaways, and Other Promotions_** **.** If you choose to enter into a sweepstakes, giveaway, or other promotion, it is possible that we may provide or share your information with third parties that TCL partners with to conduct marketing activities or that TCL engages in a sponsorship with; with third parties that administer such sweepstakes, giveaway, or other promotion; and, share your name and/or social media identity with the public if you are a winner of a prize or as required by law.

**_Mergers, Acquisitions, Business Combinations, and other Legal._**   If we are acquired by another company, or we acquire another company, your information may be shared with the acquiring company or the newly-formed company. In addition, if any bankruptcy proceeding is brought against us, any information held by the company could be sold or transferred to one or more third parties.

**_Legal Disclosures; Safety_** _.   _TCL may disclose your personal information and data to one or more third parties to remain in compliance with a legal obligation, such as in a lawsuit or similar legal proceeding; if a federal, state, or local law requires such disclosure; if an investigation has been undertaken by a governmental agency; or, in the ordinary course of business to protect our rights, property, or safety of third parties or the public.

**_Aggregate Non-Personal Information and Data_** **.** We may share with certain third parties what is commonly referred to as aggregate information, or sometimes referred to as anonymous information, of a non-personal nature, with third parties for the purpose of marketing or data analytics. No personally identifying information is disclosed in this instance.

**4\. TCL ROKU TELEVISIONS; ROKU SERVICES; THE ROKU APP**

TCL incorporates the Roku® operating system and certain Roku-enabled channels and services in its TCL® Roku TV™. When setting up a Roku account during the initial set-up of the TCL Roku TV, and during any subsequent changes made to your Roku account, you may enter certain personal information as well as user names and passwords for payment capabilities and home network internet access. TCL does not, as a matter of policy, collect the information you provide when setting up your Roku account. TCL does not collect information on your television viewing habits, on the shows and movies you choose to watch, or on any aggregated data based on your use of the TCL Roku TV. No information about your search history, or information from voice searches that you may have conducted, is obtained or in the possession of TCL. In addition, TCL does not obtain this data from Roku or other third parties that may have information, aggregated or otherwise, about you.

Owners of the TCL Roku TV can download the Roku Mobile Application for use on their mobile devices. This application provides, among other things, a remote control that allows users to control their TCL Roku TV and perform other functions. TCL does not obtain any data from your use of the Roku application, aggregate or otherwise.

Roku has its own privacy policy that provides information on how it uses data as it relates to the TCL Roku TV, the  _[www.roku.com](http://www.roku.com/)_  website, the Roku Mobile Application, and related Roku applications. The following information is intended to provide you with access to these Roku policies, so you can obtain the information you may want to know:

For Roku’s privacy policy, please visit  _<https://docs.roku.com/doc/userprivacypolicy/en-us>_.

For Roku’s website terms of use, please visit  _<https://docs.roku.com/doc/tos/en-us>_.

For Roku’s policy on its use of cookies, please visit  _<https://docs.roku.com/doc/cookiepolicy/en-us>_.

For more information on third-party channels and services offered through the TCL Roku TV, please visit the Roku website to learn more at  _[www.roku.com](http://www.roku.com/)_.

To view the End-User License Agreement (EULA) for the TCL Roku TV, select the TV model from the  _[www.tclusa.com](http://www.tclusa.com/)_  website and download the product User Guide. The EULA is located toward the end of the User Guide.

**5\. YOUR CHOICES AND OPT-OUT**

The  _[www.tclusa.com](http://www.tclusa.com/)_  website uses cookies. It is up to you whether you adjust your browser or operating system settings to limit tracking capabilities or to decline the use of cookies. For more information on how to adjust the browser or operating system settings to limit or disable the use of cookies, please refer to the supporting website or manual for your browser or operating system. If you are using a mobile device, there are generally privacy settings, and advertising settings, that you can control.

We may use cookies, or other technologies provided by third parties, to deliver specific advertising and to link the information and data collected across multiple platforms (i.e., separate computers or mobile devices) that you may be using.

We, or third parties we conduct business activities with or contract with, may initiate the placement, or provide for the recognition, of unique cookies (or similar technologies) on your browser when you visit the  _[www.tclusa.com](http://www.tclusa.com/)_  website to collect information about your other online activities over time, and may use this information to provide interest-based advertising in the form of advertisements that are more relevant to your alleged interests, as you use your browser.

We encourage you to become educated about such interest-based advertising, and to decide for yourself whether you want to utilize these technologies or to opt-out. If you wish to opt-out, please visit the following:

For companies in the United States participating in the Digital Advertising Alliance (“DAA”) please visit*: http://www.aboutads.info/choices/

For mobile devices (as above), please visit*: http://www.aboutads.info/appchoices/

If you would like to opt-out from National Advertising Initiative (“NAI”) member companies using your online activity information for online behavioral advertising, please visit*: http://www.networkadvertising.org/choices/

*Important note: the above opt-out selections may not eliminate all interest-based advertising from your computer or mobile device.

If you would like to learn more about the management of certain privacy and storage settings as they relate to “Flash cookies”, please visit: https://www.adobe.com/support/documentation/en/flashplayer/help/settings_manager.html

If you wish to correct or update any of your personal information with TCL, you may e-mail us at  _[privacy@tcl.com](mailto:privacy@tcl.com)_.

If you wish to unsubscribe from any marketing e-mails, newsletters, or other communications, please follow the instructions contained within each corresponding communication, or send a request to  _[privacy@tcl.com](mailto:privacy@tcl.com)_.

**California Residents**

In the State of California, the law provides a pathway for residents to request specific details about what companies know about them. Specifically, residents can ask to be shown their personal information that a company has in order to know what information may be used for direct marketing purposes, or shared with third party companies or other affiliated organizations. If you are a California resident, and want to make such a request, please send us an e-mail at:  _[privacy@tcl.com](mailto:privacy@tcl.com)_. You must place in the subject line of the e-mail the following statement “My California Information Privacy Rights”. TCL is not responsible if any e-mails sent are not labeled properly or do not have the complete information. TCL will take steps to ensure the security of such information, and will verify proper identification for all inquiries.

**6\. CHILDREN'S PRIVACY (UNDER AGE 13)**

We believe that protecting the privacy of children is important, and we do not knowingly collect any personal information or data from children under the age of thirteen (13). If we learn that a child under the age of thirteen (13) has provided personally identifiable information through the  _[www.tclusa.com](http://www.tclusa.com/)_  website, we will use all reasonable efforts available to us to remove such information from our files. If you wish to alert us to a child under the age of thirteen (13) that has provided personal information, please send an e-mail to us at  _[privacy@tcl.com](mailto:privacy@tcl.com)_.

**7\. SECURITY OF YOUR INFORMATION**

We use certain reasonable security measures to help protect your personal information. It is not 100% guaranteed that information electronically transmitted or stored is handled in a completely full-proof manner. It is important to note that TCL cannot warrant the security of the information you electronically transmit to us, and that it is done at your own risk. In the event that we share information with a third-party organization (as outlined in this Privacy Policy), we will use all reasonable efforts to ensure that the third parties retain the information in a secure manner and only use the information on terms and conditions that are consistent with this Privacy Policy.

**8\. THIRD-PARTY WEBSITES**

The  _[www.tclusa.com](http://www.tclusa.com/)_  website contains links to other websites that TCL does not own or operate. This includes links to certain federal, state, and local government websites, as well as private company websites, in order to provide our customers with more information about electronics recycling and donation in their local communities. This may also include links from service providers, advertisers, business partners, company sponsors, and other third-party organizations that may use the company’s logo as part of a separate agreement. We are not responsible for these sites, or any third-party sites, or the content, products, services or privacy policies or practices on these sites. These other web sites may send their own cookies to your computer or mobile device, and they may independently collect data or solicit personal information. We encourage you to locate and read each third-party website’s privacy policy. You should also independently decide for yourself the authenticity of any third-party website, as well as the claims made on that website and any links they may provide to  _[www.tclusa.com](http://www.tclusa.com/)_.

TCL may provide information on the  _[www.tclusa.com](http://www.tclusa.com/)_  website to inform consumers where certain products can be purchased, and may also provide links to certain third-party websites for our customers’ convenience.

TCL is a participant in the Amazon Services LLC Associates Program, an affiliate advertising program designed to provide a means for us to earn fees by linking to Amazon.com and affiliated sites.

**9\. INTERNATIONAL TRANSFER AND PROCESSING CONSENT**

TCL is a business with international affiliated companies and third-party organizations, and the company, or one of its affiliates, may store, transfer, or process information about you on servers located in other countries, in addition to those in the United States. Due to this, your personal information and data may be subject to the laws of other countries governing data protection that may differ materially from the United States. It is possible that your personal information may be disclosed in response to government authority requests, or in other cases in order to respond to judicial process. By using the  _[www.tclusa.com](http://www.tclusa.com/)_  website, or by providing TCL with any personal information, you consent to the collection, processing, maintenance and transfer of such information in and to the United States and other applicable countries and territories in which the privacy laws in place, now or in the future, may not be equivalent to, or in close association with, the United States, or in the country where you reside now and/or in which you are a citizen.

**10\. CHANGES & OTHER PRIVACY POLICIES**

If we make any changes to our Privacy Policy, those changes will be incorporated into the Privacy Policy and posted on this page. If you do not agree, or consent, to the updates or changes that are implemented to this Privacy Policy, please do not continue to use the  _[www.tclusa.com](http://www.tclusa.com/)_ website. In the event that we implement a material change to this Privacy Policy, we will note such a change and provide sufficient notice of its implementation.

In addition to this Privacy Policy, there may be specific promotions, sweepstakes, giveaways, or other events that will be governed by other, or additional, privacy terms. We encourage you to read any such additional terms or policies before participating in those promotions, sweepstakes, giveaways, or events, as compliance with those terms will be a requirement of participation. Any additional privacy policies, or terms, will be made available to you for your review.

**11\. CONTACT US**

If you have any questions or concerns regarding this Privacy Policy, please contact us at:

Attn:  Website Privacy Policy Administrator   
Address: TTE Technology, Inc., 1860 Compton Ave. Corona, CA 92881     
Re: TCL USA Privacy Policy Inquiry

E-Mail:  _[privacy@tcl.com](mailto:privacy@tcl.com)_  or go to  _[www.tclusa.com](http://www.tclusa.com/)_  and use the Contact Us link.

**Supplemental Contact Information**

If you have a Roku account, and you wish to update, change, delete, or otherwise edit your personal information, please contact  _[customer.advocate@roku.com](mailto:customer.advocate@roku.com)_.

You may opt-out of Roku e-mails or other similar Roku marketing that you have previously elected to receive using the methods provided in each corresponding communication, or you may contact  _[customer.advocate@roku.com](mailto:customer.advocate@roku.com)_.

If you have any questions regarding Roku’s privacy policy, you may e-mail  _[privacy@roku.com](mailto:privacy@roku.com)_.
